Marat Saytakov · Senior iOS Software Engineer · Résumé · CV

Introduction

My name is Marat Saytakov. I am an iOS software engineer with over 5 years of experience. I am proficient in Objective-C, but I prefer Swift.

I graduated from Moscow State Technical University, where I studied computer science and microchip programming. I have an <u>Engineer's degree</u> in Information Systems.

Currently I live in Moscow, but I am ready to relocate for the right position.

Skills

Deep knowledge in Objective-C and Swift, memory management, and asynchronous behavior. 99 % crash-free apps.

Short-list: iOS SDK & frameworks, ARC, GCD, plain C, Design Patterns, CocoaPods/Swift Package Manager, Git, OOP, Protocol-Oriented Programming, Apple HIG.

Contact

GitHub:

Email: remarr@gmail.com

m4rr

Web: <u>m4rr.ru</u>

LinkedIn: maratsaytakov

Languages

Russian (native), English (fluent)

Collaboration

Apple **Swift contributor** on GitHub · 2016 I started contributing to Swift with small things. github.com/apple/swift

Code Mentor · 2015—Present

I am a code mentor, covering expertise of Swift, plain C, Objective-C and Xcode. codementor.io/m4rr

Moscow Coding School · 2015—Present

Mentoring students at an in-person Swift programming course. moscoding.ru/ios

CocoaHeads Moscow · 2013—Present

Active member of Moscow iOS/OS X developers community. Given talks:

- <u>iOS Custom Keyboards</u> (2015, round table)
- Size Classes (2014, in Russian)

Employment

Freelance iOS developer · 2015—Present

Tested Upwork member. Top 30% in iOS Programming Test; Top 20% in Swift Test.

WirelessHeads · <u>pasteapp.me</u> · Oct. 2015—Present · Lead iOS Developer Working on Paste for iOS — clipboard history manager for Mac. Made decision on multiplatform sync of CoreData.

Luuk · <u>luuk.com</u> · October 2014—Sep. 2015 · Lead iOS Developer Luuk is the top beauty-industry startup in Moscow. I released both of the current versions of the apps, which were created in Swift. It has had 30k downloads in the first month and has been 99% crash free.

RocketBank · <u>rocketbank.ru</u> · Sep. 2013—Sep. 2014 · iOS Developer Released a RocketBank based MVP of a card-to-card mobile application, as well as developed the second version of RocketBank app with a fellow programmer.

Aic · <u>aic.ru</u> · August 2012—August 2013 · iOS Developer Prototyped a mobile app for <u>Money Inc</u>, a future banking concept. It is a simple way to manage your banking accounts.

Self Employment · <u>m4rr.ru</u> · 2008—2012 · Developer Made projects using pure C, Parser, JavaScript and Objective-C (since iOS 5).

Side Projects

Moscow Underground Wi-Fi Auth · m4rr.ru/mauth · App Store · GitHub Everyone in Moscow Metro has to waste a lot of time to get authorized thru overcomplicated Wi-Fi Captive portal. I solved this problem: this app takes care of authorization process for the user. Very popular among Muscovites. Open-source.

Chars · chars.cc · App Store

Beautiful and native way to type everything with Unicode characters on iOS.

Easy Percent · App Store

An easier and prettier calculator for taxes and reverse percentages.

Education

Engineer's degree in Information Systems at the Faculty of Cybernetics in Moscow State University of Radio-engineering, Electronics and Automation (MIREA has H+ rate) September 2007—July 2012